Name: Leandro Rodrigues de Souza

Position: Senior DBA, Data Engineer, SQL Developer

E-mail: leandrosouza.dba@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leandrosouzadba
Github: https://github.com/LeandroSouzaDBA/Resume

• Profile:

Leandro's main background is in Databases Administration since 2008, advanced customer and systems supports.

He has experience with SQL Developer, Data Analyst and Technical Documents/Manuals creation; He also has experience with Cloud, Virtualization, On Premise Hardware Infrastructure and Linux Operational Systems.

Ease of learning new technologies (self-taught), improving, adapting approach and teamwork. English Proficiency is B2.

• Personal Interests:

He loves to travel, drink beers and make barbecues, stay with your family and friends, learn about the universe and technologies. In addition, he have a great old video games collection.

• Education:

Bachelor's degree - Information Systems (Systems Analyst)

Franca University (UNIFRAN) 2001 – 2005

• Main Skills:

- o OracleDB
- o PostgresqlDB
- o MSSqlServerDB
- o Linux (General)
- o Shell and Python
- Support for Advanced Users
- o Virtualization (Cloud and On-Premise)
- Hardware Infrastructure

• More Skills:

Openstack, VMWare, KVM, PL/SQL, T-SQL, MongoDB, MysqlDB, MariaDB, Scrum, Github, Python, Shell Script, Bash, AWS, Azure, Windows and Linux OS: (RedHat/Ubuntu/AIX/Solaris/more), ERP PeopleSoft, Oracle SAP, and more.

• Experiences:

Trópico SA | Senior DBA | Home Office after 2020 Pandemic 2017 to nov/2024

Telecommunications Company

- Costumers Telecom Companies Support: OI, Telefônica, Vivo, Claro and Embratel.
- Support for Advanced Users/Analysts/Developers.
- Postgresql and Oracle Stand Alone and Dataguard Administration.
- Backup/Restore with RMAN, Expdp and Impdp.
- Database Monitoring, Performance Tuning and Issues Troubleshooting.
- Hardware Installation and Configuration.
- Physics and Virtual Servers Administration with VMWare, OracleVM and KVM.
- Openstack Infrastructure Creation, Hardware and System Requirements.
- Hardware Infrastructure on AWS Cloud.
- Operational Systems Linux and Windows Installation and Configuration.
- Operational Systems Advanced Support.
- Advanced Shell Scripts.
- Own Systems Supports.
- HAProxy (Processes Balancing), KeepAlived, ETHs Bond.
- Technical Documents Creation.

24x7 DBA Sênior Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Magazine Luiza | Senior DBA | On Site 2012 to 2016 Large Retail Company

- Methodologies: ITIL v3, LEAN IT, Kaizen.
- PeopleSoft: PeopleTools, ProcessScheduler, Tuxedo, WebServer, Domain.
- Oracle 10g to 12c Stand Alone, PSU, Fixes and Migrations.
- Oracle RAC, Grid Infrastructure, OEM, Dataguard, ASM, RMAN.
- Oracle PLSQL, SQLTune, AWR, Expdp, Impdp, Load and Treat Data.
- MSSQLServer 2008 2012, Cluster, TSQL, Report Services, Bkp/Restore.

24x7 DBA Sênior Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Softon Sistemas Inteligentes | Senior DBA | On Site 2011 to 2012

Antifraud Banking Company

- Costumers Bank Support: Caixa Econômica Federal, Banrisul and Banco Renner.
- Database Infrastructure in Cloud Amazon AWS.
- Oracle 10g to 11g Stand Alone.
- Postgresql 8 to 9.
- Tuning with Big Data.

IBM Brazil | Prime DBA | Hybrid – On Site and Home Office 2008 to 2011

Worldwide Technology Company

- Oracle 8i to 11g Stand Alone SAP Basis and Relacional, DR-Desaster Recovery in IBM-AIX.
- SQLServer 2000/05/08 Relacional, AS, IS, RS, TLSQL, Windows Server Cluster.
- Tuning, Monitoring, Support to Advanced Users, Infrastructure, Issues Troubleshooting, more.

DBA PRIME (Senior):

OnSite: - TECBAN and SAINTGOBAIN Companies.

Online: – WTORRE, ODEBRECHT, CARREFOUR, CYRELLA, NEXXERA, SOFISA, COPERSUCAR, Others.

Working with Projects and Ongoing.

24x7 DBA Prime Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Cadbury Adams Brazil | Junior DBA | On Site 2005 to 2008

Worldwide Food/Candy Company

- DBA/AD: Oracle9i and SQLServer2000.
- Projects Analise and Management.
- Level 1 and 2 Support: Service-Center Team Leader, Support for Advanced Users, Computer Equipments Support.

Support on trips in national territory.

• Other Experiences (On Sites):

Atento: (Level 2 Support Analyst – Telefônica Speedy) – 2007 (at night).

Unifran: (Trainee – Informatics Student Center) – 2002-2004. **Autonomous:** (Home Computing Technician) – 1997-2002.

• Certifications and Trainings:

- o PYTHON Hashtag Treinamentos 2023.
- o AWS Summit and Webinars EC2, S3, AMI, VPC, RDS, others 2022 and 2023.
- o AZURE (Az-900) Fundamentals Ka Solutions 2023.
- SCRUM Ka Solutions 2017.
- o ORACLE Workshop I e II Ka Solutions 2016.
- o GUOB and ORACLE OPEN WORLD (Brazil) 2014, 2015, and 2016.
- ORACLE Database 12c 2015.
- ITIL Foundation v3 2010 and 2013.
- o ORACLE Database 10g, 11g 2006 and 2010.